As long as modern-day crimes involve people,
،طالما جرائم العصر الحديث تتضمّن بشراً
there are no unsolvable mysteries!
!لا توجد ألغاز لا تُحلّ
Today's case is about Conan's origin!
قضيّة اليوم عن أصل كونان
And the detective from out west makes a reappearance!
!ويعاود متحرّيو الغرب الظهور
He sees the single truth for what it is,
يرى الحقيقة الواحدة
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
يحمل مظهر طفل، لكنّ عقله عقل بالغ
His name? Detective Conan!
!اسمه المتحرّي كونان
The Holmes Freak Murder Case (Part 1)
(جريمة قتل مهووس هولمز (الجزء الأوّل
Sherlock Holmes Enthusiasts Reception Tour
جولة استقبال مهووسي شارلوك هولمز
"A Study in Scarlet"?
دراسة في اللون القرمزي" إذاً"
Yes...
أجل
It is noteworthy as the very first story Sherlock Holmes appears in!
إنّه عمل مميّز كان فيه !الظهور الأوّل لهولمز
"The Red-Headed League" is my favorite!
!عصبة ذوي الشعر الأحمر" هو المفضّل لي"
Mine's "The Sign of Four"!
!"أنا! عملي المفضّل هو "علامة الأربعة
Oh! That one was internationally acclaimed!
!ذاك عمل لقي تقديراً عالمياً
Impressive, my boy! You can read kanji?
مذهل يا فتى، يمكنك قراءة الكانجي؟
Yeah...
نوعاً ما
Gimme a break.
...يا إلهي، هؤلاء
Why do I have to go on this stupid tour?
لمَ عليّ المشاركة في هذه الجولة السخيفة؟
Because Conan-kun applied for you without asking...
لأنّ كونان-كن أرسل طلب المشاركة قبل السؤال
And then I was unlucky enough to get picked...
...ثمّ كان حظّي سيئاً ما يكفي بحيث تمّ اختيارنا
Ugh.
...يا إلهي
Which story do you favor?
أيّ قصة هي المفضلة لديك؟
Who, me?
ماذا؟ أ-أنا؟
Yes.
أجل
Good question.
...حسناً، سؤال جيّد
I'd say I prefer "And Then There Was One."
أرى "ثمّ كان هناك أحد" المفضّلة لي
That's "And Then There Were None."
"تقصد "ثمّ لم يكن هناك أحد
Yoshiaki Fuji (47)
(فوجيساوا توشياكي (47 موظّف محطّة قطار
And that novel was written by Agatha Christie,
وتلك رواية ألفّتها أغاثا كريستي
Nanako Shimizu (24) - Librarian
(شيميزو ناناكو (24 أمينة مكتبة
not my beloved Conan Doyle-sama.
وليس كونان دويل-ساما الذي أقدّره
My word.
عجباً
Ikuo Kawatsu (25) - Gym Teacher
(كاواتسو إيكو (25 أستاذ رياضة في الثانوية
Who let this amateur on the tour?
لم أعلم أن بيننا هواة في هذه الجولة
Talk about a real party pooper...
يا لمُفسد الجوّ
I'm supposed to live with these jerks for three whole days?!
عليّ البقاء مع هؤلاء لثلاثة أيام كاملة؟
These aren't the only guests.
ليسوا الضيوف الوحيدين
As we speak,
يصطحب مُشرف الجولة بقيّة الضيوف
the tour director is in another car,
(إيواي هيتومي (24 عاملة نُزل
taking the other guests back to the lodge!
في سيّارة أخرى للنُزل في هذه الأثناء
Oh man...
...مهلك
Oh, come on. The more the merrier!
!ما المشكلة؟ زاد العدد زادت المتعة
I'll give you merrier!
!كيف ذلك؟
Ouch!
!مؤلم
Welcome, everyone, to the Mycroft Lodge!
"مرحباً بكم يا سادة في نُزلي هذا، "ماي كروفت
I'm Kanaya, the director of this tour
أنا كانايا، مُشرف هذه الجولة
and this lodge's owner!
ومالك النُزل
Each one of you here today
كلّ واحد بينكم اليوم
is a superior Sherlockian that I have carefully selected.
معجب شارلوكيّ اخترته بعناية
Are you sure you were careful enough?
هل اخترت بعناية حقّاً؟
It seems a complete amateur who knows nothing about Holmes
يبدو أنّ بيننا مبتدئاً لا يفقه أيّ شيء
is among us.
عن هولمز
Oh? Is there really?
ماذا؟ حقّاً؟
Maria Toda (43) - Fortuneteller
(تودا ماريا (43 قارئة طالع
Over there. That mustached man.
انظري، ذاك الرجل المشورب
Oh, my.
...يا إلهي
That's it. I'm out of here.
اكتفيت، سأغادر
Please wait, Mori-san!
!ا-انتظر رجاءً يا موري-سان
This man I've brought here today is none other
يا سادة، الرجل الذي جلبتُه اليوم هو العَلم عينه
than the great, modern-day detective that compares with
متحرّي العصر الحديث العظيم الذي يُقارن بشخصيتنا المحبوبة هولمز
Kogoro Mori-san, right?
موري كوغورو-سان، صحيح؟
I know who he is.
أعرفه
I've seen him many a time on TV and in the papers.
فقد رأيتُه مرات عديدة في التلفاز والصحف
He certainly appears
يبدو أنّه يملك ذكاءً حاداً بالفعل
Kento Togano (22) - University Student
(توغانو كينتو (22 طالب جامعيّ، رئيس نادي التحرّي
but he clearly doesn't compare
لكن يستحيل أن يُقارن بشارلوك
Certainly not.
صحيح
ln a real contest,
لن تبلغ موضع قدميه
Ayako Oki (21) - University Student
(أوكي أياكو (21 طالبة جامعية، عضو في نادي التحرّي
you probably wouldn't even begin
في منافسة حقيقية على الأرجح
I can't let them get away with saying that!
!لا يمكنني تركهم يقولون هذا
Now, now.
هوّن عليك
You're being compared with Holmes; it's to be expected!
أنت تُقارن بهولمز فلا عجب
You shut up!
!اخرس
I refuse to lose to a stupid fictional character!
!أرفض الخسارة لشخصية كتب خيالية
Besides, this is all because you signed me up for this tour!
!كلّ هذا لأنّك سجّلتني في هذه الجولة
Conan-kun!
!كونان-كن
Conan?!
كونان؟
Truly?!
حقّاً؟
I like it too! Isn't it a great name?!
يعجبني أيضاً، أليس اسماً رائعاً؟
It's magnificent!
!مُبهر
I guess I didn't need to worry after all.
يبدو أنّه لم تكن هناك حاجة للقلق
Conan-kun's usually cool and strangely un-childlike.
فكونان-كن متّزن وغير طفوليّ في العادة بشكل غريب
But as I look at that innocent face of his, I feel relieved.
عندما أنظر لوجهه البريء هذا أشعر بالراحة
But Conan-kun's fascination with Holmes is almost the same as his!
لكن هوسه بهولمز يجعله يبدو مثله
His?
مثله؟
You know who!
!تعرف من أقصد
He's snobbish and arrogant,
مُتباهٍ ومغرور
a mystery nerd, a Holmes freak, and is tone--
...ومُحب للتحرّي وأحد مهووسي هولمز، وأصمّ
...tone-deaf, but a superb high school soccer player,
أصمّ النغم، لكن لاعب كرة قدم بارع في المرحلة الثانويّة
and the guy who ran off during our contest the other day
ومن هرب أثناء مواجهتنا في ذاك اليوم
before I could recoup my losses...
...قبل أن أستطيع ردّ اعتباري
...Shinichi Kudo, right?
كودو شينتشي، صحيح؟
Hattori-kun!
!هاتّوري-كن
You're a Holmes fan too?!
أنت أحد معجبي هولمز أيضاً؟
Of course not!
!كلا
The reason I applied for this tour
سبب تقديمي على هذه الجولة
was 'cuz I thought I might find Kudo.
هو لأنّي ظننت أني قد ألتقي كودو
Besides, Ellery Queen's much better than Conan Doyle--
كما أنّ إيليري كوين تروقني أكثر من كونان دويل
On second thought, maybe Doyle's better!
!لكن لعلّ لدويل الكعب الأعلى
It's growing late, so we'll call it a night.
تأخّر الوقت يا سادة لذا لنخلد للراحة
Breakfast is tomorrow morning at 9:00,
الإفطار غداً عند التاسعة صباحاً
lunch at 1:00, and dinner at 8:00.
والغداء عند الواحدة والعشاء عند الثامنة
And then after dinner is the annual super-difficult mystery quiz!
وبعد العشاء ستُقام مسابقة !التحرّي المعقّدة السنوية
And those who get a perfect score on the quiz
ومن يحصلون على علامة كاملة في المسابقة
will be presented with Conan Doyle's greatest work
سيتلقون أعظم أعمال كونان دويل
which brought Sherlock Holmes into this world--
الذي جلب شارلوك هولمز لهذا العالم
a first-edition copy of "A Study in Scarlet!"
"نسخة إصدار أوّل من "دراسة في اللون القرمزيّ
However!
لكن
First, I must see proof of how devoted you are to Holmes!
عليكم أن تروني دليل مدى إخلاصكم لهولمز أوّلاً
Proof?
دليل؟
What my maid is passing out right now
ما ستوزّعه الخادمة عليكم الآن
is the Holmes Cult Test of 1000 Questions!
هو اختبار طائفة هولمز ذو ألف سؤال
1000 questions?!
!أ-ألف سؤال؟
You have until dinner tomorrow evening to turn it in.
أمامكم حتّى العشاء غداً لتسليمه
Only those who get over 990 correct
وحدهم من يجيبون بشكل صحيح على ما يفوق 990 سؤال
will be able to participate in tomorrow's quiz.
سيمكنهم المشاركة في مسابقة الغد
Just to be safe, if you have a cell phone
للحيطة، إذا كانت معكم هواتف
or any Holmes-related literature,
أو أيّ أعمال متعلّقة بهولمز
please hand them over to my maid now.
عليكم تسليمها للخادمة الآن
There's no point in trying to hide them!
لا جدوى من محاولة إخفائها
Placed throughout the lodge to watch over you
فيوجد في أرجاء النُزل كاميرات مراقبة
are security cameras and listening devices!
!كما أجهزة تنصّت لمراقبتكم
If you're caught cheating, you will be asked to leave at once!
إذا تم ضبط غشّ أحدكم، سيُطلب منه المغادرة فوراً
Hey, now. Do I have to take that test too?
هل عليّ أخذ هذا الاختبار أيضاً؟
Certainly not; you're a special guest.
كلا، أنت ضيف خاص
All I ask is that you give us a lecture later on...
نرجو أن تعطينا كلمةً فحسب لاحقاً
Hey. If I get over 990 right, can I be in the quiz too?
،لو أجبتُ على ما يفوق 990 سؤالاً أيمكنني المشاركة في المسابقة أيضاً؟
Sure...
...أ-أجل
Let's see...
...حسناً
"What was the exact date that Holmes fell
ما كان تاريخ سقوط هولمز
to the bottom of the valley with Professor Moriarty?"
في قاع الوادي مع البروفسور موريارتي؟
May 4th, 1891.
الرابع من مايو عام 1891
This is actually pretty easy!
!هذا سهل
Next one...
...التالي
"Write down the entire code from 'The Dancing Men'
(اكتب الشفرة الكاملة من (مغامرة الرجال الراقصين"
exactly as it appeared."
"كما ظهرت تماماً
Conan-kun...
...كونان-كن
Are you still up? It's 4 o'clock, you know.
لا تزال مستيقظاً؟ إنّها الرابعة
Ugh. No TV, no phones, no newspapers...
يا إلهي، لا تلفاز ولا هاتف ولا صحف
On top of that, there's not even any air-conditioning,
وفوقها، لا يوجد أيّ جهاز تبريد
despite this heat!
!مع هذه الحرارة
A single security camera is all there is.
فقط كاميرا مراقبة واحدة
This is the best!
!هذا رائع
That was great!
!أكلتُ كثيراً
The owner hasn't shown up at all, has he?
لم يظهر المالك أبداً
Go get him and start grading the tests already!
!ناديه بسرعة وليبدأ تصحيح الاختبارات
But I've been told to entertain you all until he comes...
لـ-لكنه أخبرني أن أهتم بخدمتكم ريثما يصل
Kudo ain't here. I shouldn't have come on this tour...
كودو ليس موجوداً، كان عليّ ألا آتي لهذه الجولة
Damn it! I've had enough of this!
!تبّاً! اكتفيت
I'm going to my room!
!سأذهب لأستريح في غرفتي
Sir!
!سيّدي
Sounds like the rumors were true...
يبدو أنّ الشائعات كانت صحيحة
He was lying when he said he would give away
كان يكذب عندما قال أنّه سيقدّم
that first-edition copy.
نسخة إصدار أوّل للفائز بالمسابقة
He finds fault in people's answers every time,
يتصنع عيوباً في إجابات المشاركين كلّ مرة
and makes it so nobody ever wins.
ولا يجعل أحداً يفوز
He only holds this tour to show off that book of his!
يقيم هذه الجولة للاستعراض بكتابه وحسب
Sorry, but I'm going to sleep too.
آسفة، لكنّي سأذهب للنوم أيضاً
Same here.
وأنا
Um!
...عذراً
This is ridiculous. I'm going to bed too.
سخافة، سأخلد للنوم بدوري
What now, Conan-kun?
ماذا ستفعل يا كونان-كن؟
I'm going to stay here.
سأبقى هنا
Oh, man. I'm at my limit, too.
...وصلت حدّي أيضاً
Come on, Kento. Let's go back to our room, too.
كينتو، لنعد إلى غرفتنا كذلك
Be patient! Making a move at a time like this would mean defeat!
اصبري، الإقدام على حركة في وقت كهذا يعني الخسارة
Huh? Isn't that the car we came in?
ماذا؟ أليست السيّارة التي أتينا بها؟
That's the owner! He's driving!
!ذاك المالك! إنّه يقودها
See, the mystery quiz is finally starting.
رأيتم؟ ستبدأ مسابقة التحرّي أخيراً
That's my Kento.
كما يُتوقّع منك يا كينتو
Wait!
...لـ-لحظة
There's a cliff there!
أمامه جرف
Oh no! It's speeding up!
!كلا! ارتفعت السرعة
Hey, Mister! What're you doin'?!
أنت، يا سيّد! ما الذي تفعله؟
Stop the car before you drive off!
!أوقف السيّارة قبل أن تسقط
There's a blanket on the car's panel!
!توجد مُلاءة على مقصورة السيّارة
And what's that sound?! It's not the engine!
وما هذا الصوت؟ ليس صوت المحرك
Hey! Mister! I'm talking to you!
!أنت! يا سيّد! أتسمعني؟
What? The owner's dead?!
ماذا؟ مات المالك؟
Yes.
أجل، صحيح
He drove off the cliff just now before our very eyes!
قاد السيّارة حتى سقط من الجرف أمام أنظارنا قبل قليل
That can't be! Why would he do that?!
لا يُعقل! لمَ قد يفعل ذلك؟
It was a suicide.
كان انتحاراً
He probably didn't want to part with his first-edition book.
لم يرد مفارقة إصدار كتاب هولمز الأوّل خاصته غالباً
No, this just might've been a murder!
كلا، قد تكون جريمة قتل
Someone put him to sleep or killed him in advance,
نوّم أحدهم المالك أو قتله سلفاً
sat him in the car seat,
ثم أجلسه في مقعد السيّارة
and put the car in drive to make it move forward automatically.
ووضع ناقل الحركة في وضعية القيادة لتتحرك من نفسها تلقائياً
The killer most likely did all of that inside that garage.
قام القاتل بكلّ ذلك داخل ذاك المرآب غالباً
Then does that mean one of us is the killer?!
أيعني هذا أنّ القاتل أحدنا؟
Yes, something like that.
أجل، غالباً
That may be, but the car sped up at one point!
ربما، لكن ارتفعت سرعة السيّارة في مرحلة
There was also a strange hissing sound coming from inside!
كما كان هناك صوت أشبه بهسيس بالرياح من داخلها
It wasn't the engine!
لم يكن المحرك
Oh, that must have been the air conditioner!
لا بد أنّه كان صوت جهاز التبريد
The AC was set to on, so when the engine was started
،كان مفتاحه مضبوطاً على التشغيل فعندما أدار المحرك
it kicked in by itself!
اشتغل تلقائياً
At any rate, the body is unrecoverable.
بأيّ حال، لا يمكننا استرجاع جثته
Our only choice is to contact the police and wait.
خيارنا الوحيد هو الاتّصال بالشرطة والانتظار
But the owner took all our phones...
لكنّ المالك أخذ كلّ هواتفنا
They must be in his room!
!لا بدّ أنّها في غرفته
Oh? What are you looking at that tire track for?
ماذا؟ لمَ تنظر لآثار الإطارات؟
Just looking for something...
...أبحث عن شيء فحسب
Not you too, Hattori-kun?
حتّى أنت يا هاتّوري-كن
Don't look at me! I was just checking to see
لا تنظري لي! كنتُ أتحقق ما إن كان
if the AC was really on or not!
!جهاز التبريد يعمل أم لا فحسب
And then I run into this kid again--
...ثمّ ارتطمتُ بهذا الصبيّ مُجدداً
Wait a minute!
مُجدداً؟
He also collided with me when I was looking for evidence
ارتطم بي عندما كنت أبحث عن دليل
during that previous incident!
في القضيّة السابقة أيضاً
It's too dark to see well, huh?
لا يمكن الرؤية في الظلام، صحيح؟
Yeah...
...أ-أجل
How's this, young detectives?
ما رأيكما بهذا أيّها المتحرّيان الصغيران؟
Thanks...
.شكراً
Much obliged...
نقدّر هذا
The phones have been demolished!
!حُطّمت الهواتف
Who would do such a thing?!
مـ-من قد يفعل هذا؟
The first-edition book is gone too!
!اختفت نسخة الإصدار الأوّل أيضاً
Damn it! I've had enough!
!تبّاً! اكتفيت
Let's take the remaining car and get out of this place--
...لنستقلّ السيّارة الأخرى ونخرج من هذا المكان
Pointless.
لا يمكن
The car in the garage had its gas tank punctured
ثُقب خزان وقود السيّارة في المرآب
and all the gasoline has leaked out!
وتسرّب كل البنزين
On top of that, the battery's been removed.
فوق ذلك نُزعت البطّارية
That car's not going anywhere!
لن تتحرك تلك السيّارة أبداً
You can't be serious!
لا-لا يُعقل
It would seem the owner was killed by someone, Detective.
يبدو أنّ المالك قُتل بيدي أحدهم حقّاً يا حضرة المتحرّي
What kind of trick the killer used to speed the car up is a mystery,
تبقى الحيلة التي استعملها القاتل لرفع سرعة السيّارة لغزاً
but the fact that we're trapped here
...لكنّ احتجازنا هنا يعني
means that the killer still plans to continue this murder drama!
!أنّه لا يزال ينوي إكمال مسرحية القتل هذه
Whatever the case, the killer is in this room.
أيّاً يكن، القاتل بيننا
If we properly investigate we'll uncover them soon enough!
سنستأصله إذا أجرينا تحقيقاً دقيقاً
Oh, yeah! The security cameras might have recorded something!
!صـ-صحيح! ربما التقطت كاميرات المراقبة شيئاً
I'm sorry. Those aren't real.
آ-آسفة، تلك مزيّفة
He puts them up every year for this tour.
يركّبها كل عام لهذه الجولة
With thumbtacks.
بدبابيس تثبيت
Thumbtacks?
دبابيس تثبيت؟
Even so, we know it was around 3:30
مع ذلك، نعرف أنّ القاتل وضع المالك
when the killer put the owner in the car and sent him on his way.
في السيّارة وحرّكهما عند قرابة الثالثة والنصف
And that it was impossible for the five of us
وأنّ فعل ذلك كان مستحيلاً لنا نحن الخمسة
who had been in the living room for several hours prior
الذين كنا في غرفة المعيشة لعدّة ساعات قبلها
Hold on a second.
مهلك
So the killer was one of us five who weren't in the living room?!
أتقصد أنّ القاتل كان أحدنا الخمسة الذين لم يكونوا في غرفة المعيشة؟
Please refrain from counting me!
!لا تحسبني معهم رجاءً
Hey.
أخبرني
Did you find what you were looking for earlier?
أوجدتَ ما كنت تبحث عنه قبلاً؟
No, not at all...
كلا، البتّة
I see.
هكذا إذاً
Ayako?
أ-أياكو؟
I just figured out both the killer's identity and their trick.
اكتشفتُ هويّة القاتل كما حيلته
Along with conclusive evidence.
بالإضافة للدليل الدامغ
What?!
!ماذا؟
I'll give you ten minutes.
سأعطيك 10 دقائق
If you don't wish to hear your name from my mouth
إذا لم ترد أن أنطق باسمك
then you'll come clean before then.
فعليك الاعتراف قبلها
Ayako! Where are you going?!
أياكو! أين تذهبين؟
The bathroom.
الحمّام
Are you crazy? The killer might go after you if you're all alone!
أأنتِ حمقاء؟ قد يستهدفكِ القاتل !إن ذهبتِ بمفردك
Oh, but you'll protect me, won't you?
لكنّك ستحميني، أليس كذلك؟
Hey! Wait!
!انتظري
Your big reputation's on the line, huh?
سمعتك كمتحرٍّ عظيم على المحك
She's probably bluffin'.
إنّها تتحايل غالباً
No! She must have found a clue we don't know about yet!
كلا، لا بدّ أنها وجدت دليلاً لا نزال نجهله
Yeah, that must be it.
أجل، صحيح
Now that you mention it, Ayako-san was acting odd this afternoon.
بالمناسبة، كانت أياكو-سان تتصرف بغرابة نوعاً ما ظهيرة اليوم
I ran into her on the way back to my room after lunch.
التقيتُ بها في طريق عودتي للغرفة بعد الغداء
But when she saw me, she quickly hid some papers behind her.
عندما رأتني، أخفت أوراقاً بسرعة وراءها
I think it might've been the Holmes test that was passed out last night...
أظنّه كان اختبار هولمز الذي وُزّع البارحة
The test?
الاختبار؟
Don't tell me...
...أيمكن
...she was cheating?
كانت تغشّ؟
Talk about low...
يا للوضاعة
Alright! Who's the killer?!
أنت! من القاتل؟
You secretly asked her, didn't you?
سألتها سرّاً، صحيح؟
Please tell us!
!أخبرنا رجاءً
She said she wouldn't tell even me
قالت أنّها لن تخبر أحداً حتّى أنا
and then shut herself up in the bathroom.
وأغلقت على نفسها في الحمام
Damn it! How dare she taunt us!
!تبّاً! تستفزنا
Say...
...أخبريني أيّتها الخادمة
There were other people besides Ayako-san
كان هناك آخرون لم يحضروا الغداء
who skipped lunch, right?
مع أياكو-سان، صحيح؟
Yes. Just Kento Togano-san and Nanako Shimizu-san.
أجل، توغانو كينتو-سان وشيميزو ناناكو-سان
At any rate, the fact that she's suspected of cheating
بأيّ حال، كونها مشبوهة بالغشّ الآن
means that Ayako knew from the very start
يعني أنّ أياكو-سان كانت تعرف منذ البداية
that those security cameras were mock-ups!
أنّ كاميرات المراقبة تلك كانت نماذج مزيّفة
Hey.
أخبرني يا أوني-تشان
Did Ayako-san come to your room this afternoon?
هل أتت أياكو-سان لغرفتك ظهيرة اليوم؟
No. I did the rest of the test in my room,
كلا، حللتُ بقية الاختبار في غرفتي
but nobody came.
لكن لم يأت أحد
Which means she did see it in someone's room!
ما يعني أنّها رأت في غرفة أحدهم
Something significant to this incident!
شيئاً مهمّاً مرتبطاً بالقضيّة
Something that one of those four alibi-less people had--
...شيء كان في غرفة أحد هؤلاء الأربعة
--in their room!
الذين لا يملكون حجّة غياب
Isn't Ayako-san late coming back?
ألم تتأخر أياكو-سان؟
Now that you mention it...
...صـ-صحيح
It's been over twenty minutes...
مضت أكثر من 20 دقيقة
She couldn't be!
...أ-أيمكن
Hey! Ayako-san! Ayako-san!
!أياكو-سان! أياكو-سان
What's all the racket?!
لمَ الجلبة؟
It's rude of you to gather around the bathroom, you know!
من غير اللبق أن تجتمعوا عند الحمام
No, we were worried about you, so--
...كلا، كنا قلقين عليك
We'd like you to tell us who the killer is!
!كما نريدك أن تخبرينا عن هوية القاتل
Oh, that?
ذاك؟
It seems I made a mistake.
يبدو أنّي ارتكبت خطأً
I'm sorry.
آسفة
Bah. So it really was a bluff...
يا إلهي، كان تحايلاً بالفعل إذاً
Why? Why'd she suddenly change her attitude?
لمَ؟ لمَ تغيّر سلوكها فجأةً؟
Darn it! And there're so many things I don't know!
!تبّاً! وهناك أشياء كثيرة لا نعرفها
Huh? Where's Ayako-san?
ماذا؟ أين أياكو-سان؟
She went for a walk outside.
ذهبت للتمشّي في الخارج
We tried to stop her,
حاولنا إيقافها
but she insisted there won't be any more murders.
لكنّها قالت أنّه لن تقع المزيد من الجرائم
Well, we do have all four suspects here, so...
...حسناً، المشتبه بهم الأربعة جميعاً هنا، لذا
Nothing will happen if we just stay still.
لن يحصل شيء إن بقينا مكاننا
What was that sound?!
!ما كان ذاك الصوت؟
It came from the garage!
!أتى من المرآب
What on earth happened?!
!ماذا حصل بالضبط؟
Don't tell me Ayako-san's in there!
أيمكن أنّ أياكو-سان في الداخل؟
Ayako! Ayako!
!أياكو... أياكو
You moron! Jump into that and you'll only burn to death!
!أحمق! إذا دخلت ستموت حرقاً وحسب
Somebody get an extinguisher!
!ليجلب أحد مطفأة حريق
There's one over here!
!توجد واحدة هناك
Please! Somebody put it out!
!أرجوكم! ليخمدها أحد بسرعة
Otherwise that book will be--
...وإلّا الكتاب
Looks like it's out.
يبدو أنّنا أخمدناها
Ayako! Where are you?!
!أياكو! أين أنت؟
Are you there?! Ayako!
!أأنت هنا؟ أياكو
What is it?!
!ما الخطب؟
Ayako?
أياكو؟
Ayako! Ayako!
!أياكو! أياكو
Judging from her clothes and figure, there's no question it's her.
بناءً على الثياب والبنية، لا شكّ أنها كانت هي
And she was perfectly fine just a short while ago...
...كانت بخير تماماً قبل قليل
Come to think of it, she did say she figured out who the killer was...
...بالمناسبة، قالت أنّها عرفت من القاتل
So the killer killed her to keep her quiet?
قتلها لإبقائها صامتة إذاً؟
But I believe all the suspects were in the owner's lodge
لكن أعتقد أنّ جميع المشتبه بهم كانوا في نُزل المالك
when the fire erupted in this garage.
عندما شبّ الحريق في المرآب
Then who set it?
من أشعله إذاً؟
It wouldn't just start by itself...
لن يبدأ من تلقاء نفسه
No, there is one person who could have done it!
كلا، كان بإمكان شخص فعل ذلك
The owner!
!المالك
He drove off the cliff, but wouldn't everything fit
،سقط من الجرف بالسيّارة لكن ألن تتصل كل الخيوط
if he were still alive?!
إن كان حيّاً؟
Yes! If it had been a dummy or something in the car, then...
أ-أجل! إذا كان ما في السيّارة ...دمية وما شابه، عندها
There was a novel like that...
...كانت هناك رواية كذلك
Nope. It was the owner, in the flesh.
كلا، كان المالك بشحمه ولحمه من في السيّارة
I saw him too! I don't think there's any question about it!
!رأيتُه أيضاً! فلا شكّ برأيي
Then who the hell did this?!
!من فعل هذا إذاً؟
Somebody's just killed Ayako!
!قتل أحدهم أياكو
Calm down!
!اهدأ
In any case, it's painfully clear that the killer is not one of us ten.
بأيّ حال، من الواضح أنّ القاتل ليس أحدنا العشرة
For now, let's retreat to the house and wait until morning.
لنرجع للمنزل حالياً وننتظر الصباح
Let's stay in the living room.
لنبق في غرفة المعيشة إذاً
As if I'd ever mistake a person for a dummy!
!كأنّي سأخلط بين دمية وبشريّ
But all the suspects were in the lodge...
لكن كان كلّ المشتبه بهم في الغرفة
Could someone have put a time-activated detonator in the garage?
أيمكن أن أحدهم وضع جهاز تفجير مؤقت في المرآب؟
No, there was nothing of the sort!
كلا، لم يكن هناك شيئاً كهذا
Then how did the killer start the fire?!
كيف أشعل القاتل الحريق إذاً؟
We don't know that, so that's why we're--
...نجهل ذلك لذا نحن الآن
What was Ayako-san doing in the garage, anyway?
ولمَ كانت أياكو-سان في المرآب بالأساس؟
It's really coming down...
المطر يهطل بغزارة
If this downpour keeps up, there's no leaving come morning...
لن نستطيع الخروج حتّى الصباح إن استمرّ هذا الهطول
I'm tired from staying up all night, not to mention hungry...
تعبتُ من السهر، كما أتضوّر جوعاً
Shall I make some coffee and something cold to eat?
هل أعدّ قهوة وأكلاً بارداً معها إذاً؟
I'll help you!
!سأساعدك
I'll come too!
سأرافقكما إذاً
I'd be worried if you two girls were all by yourselves.
فسنقلق عليكما إن كنتما بمفردكما
I'll come too.
سآتي أيضاً
But if the owner really is the killer,
لكن إذا كان المالك هو الفاعل حقاً
why would he pretend to die and then kill Ayako-san?
فلمَ تظاهر بالموت ثمّ قتل أياكو-سان؟
He's enjoying his murder!
!إنّه يستمتع بالقتل
Have a look at this card!
!انظروا لهذه البطاقة
Had I not been careful I would've been killed!
!كنتُ لألقى حتفي لو لم أتوخ الحذر
"If you want the book, then come to the garage at 5 a.m. tomorrow.
إذا أردت الكتاب فتعال للمرآب" الخامسة صباح الغد
I'll put it beneath the back seat."
"سأضعه أسفل المقعد الخلفيّ
It was past 4:30 when the fire started in the garage...
نشب الحريق في المرآب بعد الرابعة والنصف وفقما أظن
The back seat? That's where Ayako's body was!
المقعد الخلفيّ؟ كانت هناك جثّة أياكو-سان
Say, where did you get this card?
من أين أتتك البطاقة؟
It was stuck in my door when I returned from dinner last night.
وجدتُها عالقةً في باب غرفتي عندما رجعت من العشاء البارحة
That's it! I figured it out!
!هكذا إذاً! اكتشفت الأمر
Listen, Mister!
اسمع أيّها الرجل المُسن
How many times do I have to say it?! The owner was dead!
!كم مرّةً عليّ إخبارك؟! المالك ميت
Can I really trust what a kid saw?
كأنّي سأثق بما رآه طفل
What'd you say?!
!ماذا؟
Judging from where Ayako-san died,
بناءً على مكان موت أياكو-سان
it would seem that she, too, went to the garage to get the book.
فيُحتمل أنّها ذهبت للمرآب للحصول على الكتاب أيضاً
Which means the only remaining mystery of the second incident
ما يعني أنّ اللغز الوحيد المتبقي في الحادثة الثانية
is how the killer lit the garage on fire while still in the room.
هو كيف أضرم القاتل النار في المرآب بينما هو في الغرفة
And it's because of detectives like you
...بسبب متحرّيين مثلك أصلاً
that so many cases go unsolved--
...توجد قضايا كثيرة عالقة بلا حلّ
How rude!
!يا للفظاظة
My dad solves his cases every single time!
!يحلّ أبي قضاياه كلّ مرة
He takes a sleeping-like pose whenever he analyzes things,
يتّخذ وضعية نوم متى بدأ بالتحليل دوماً
so everyone fears him as "Sleeping Kogoro"!
"فيخشاه الجميع بلقب "كوغورو النائم
Right, Dad?!
صحيح يا أبي؟
Sleeping?
النائم؟
Hey! Come over here!
تعالي قليلاً
What are you doing?
ماذا؟
Where is he when your old man starts analyzing?!
أين يكون هو بينما يبدأ والدك التحليل؟
Who?
هو؟
You know, the one who's always hangin' around you guys...
...أقصد من يتطفل حولكما دوماً
This kid!
!هذا
Conan-kun?
كونان-كن؟
Now that you mention it, he never is around...
صحيح، لا يكون موجوداً في العادة
Yeah?!
حقّاً؟
Oh, but he often appears from behind my dad
لكنه يظهر من وراء أبي أحياناً
and helps explain his theories!
ويساعد بشرح استنتاجاته
From behind him?
من ورائه؟
You help from behind him?
تساعده من ورائه؟
I love to play detective!
!أحب لعب لعبة المتحرّي
A power outage?!
!انقطاع كهرباء
Was it from lightning?!
أيمكن بسبب الصواعق؟
No! It's just a blown fuse!
!كلا، إنّه مجرد مِصهر محروق
Then hurry and reset the circuit breakers!
!أسرعي وأعيدي ضبط القواطع إذاً
Damn it! Now, of all times!
...تبّاً، في وقت كهذا
Here, Miss. Use this light...
...هنا يا آنسة، استعملي هذا الضوء
An ice pick!
!كسّارة ثلج
What's going on?!
!ماذا؟! ما الذي جرى؟
What's that sound?!
!ما كان ذاك الصوت؟
Glass.
زجاج
Maid!
!الخادمة
Hurry with the lights!
!أعيدوا الكهرباء بسرعة
Fujisawa-san!
!فوجيساوا-سان
How?!
كيف؟
Dad! The window glass!
...أبي! زجاج النافذة
Dammit! They smashed the window and escaped!
!تبّاً! حطّم النافذة وهرب
No! The killer's still in here! And--
...كلا! لا يزال القاتل هنا، كما
And now I finally know how the killer set the garage on fire
كما عرفتُ أخيراً كيف أضرم القاتل الحريق في المرآب
while in this room!
!وهو في الغرفة
Perhaps the third incident wasn't part of the killer's plan?
لعلّ الحادثة الثالثة لم تكن ضمن حسابات القاتل؟
Conan-kun!
!كونان-كن
But I'm just a kid, so what would I know?
لكنّي مجرد طفل، فما الذي أعرفه؟
This kid isn't pretending to be a detective!
...لا يلعب لعبة المتحرّي
He's analyzing!
!إنّه يحلل بدقّة
His voice and body are different, but he's almost like Shinichi Kudo!
!صوته وجسده مختلفان، لكنّه يشبه كودو شينتشي
Could he really be?!
أ-أيمكن أنّه هو حقاً؟
The Holmes Freak Murder Case (Part 2)
(جريمة قتل مهووس هولمز (الجزء الثاني
On the next Conan--
في الحلقة القادمة من كونان
Next Conan's hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
Holmes' Cult Test.
اختبار طائفة هولمز
Next episode Conan's true identity is threatened.
في الحلقة القادمة، هويّة كونان !الحقيقيّة في خطر
I've figured it out.
هل اكتشفتُها؟